嘿
Hey.
嗨，宝贝
要来点鸡蛋吗？
Hi, honey.
Want some eggs?
别听她的，这根本不是鸡蛋
Don't listen to her.
lt's not eggs.
这是人工合成的狗屁鸡蛋
lt's that fake egg crap.
吃起来跟天然的一模一样
lt tastes exactly
the same.
是啊，跟天然的狗屁一模一样
Yes, exactly like crap.
你干嘛做人工鸡蛋？
Why are you making
fake eggs?
你爸爸和我昨天去了“老年人健康博览会”
Your father and l went
to the Senior Health Fair yesterday.
老年人健康博览会？
Senior Health Fair?
博览些什么啊？
What are the rides
there?
发牢骚？
The complain￡-a￡-go￡-round?
出气筒？
Tunnel of gas?
我们测了胆固醇
We had our cholesterol
checked
我们两个都接近危险界限了
and the both of us are very
close to the danger zone.
我的比她的低
Mine was lower
than hers.
只低了1个百分点
One point lower.
那我还是会活得比你长
l'm still gonna live
longer than you.
是吗？长30秒？
What, 30 seconds?
在乐园里的30秒
30 seconds in paradise.
听着，罗密欧和朱丽叶
Uh, listen,
Romeo and Juliet,
我要借个垃圾袋
l'm gonna borrow
a garbage bag.
你说借是什么意思？
难道你还要还回来？
What do you mean borrow?
You're gonna give it back?
好吧，我要偷一个垃圾袋
All right,
l'm stealing a garbage bag.
－ 这是什么鬼东西？
－ 给你冲咖啡的牛奶
￡- What the hell is that?
￡- lt's milk for your coffee.
－ 这不是我的牛奶
－ 这就是平时喝的牛奶
￡- That's not my milk.
￡- That's regular milk.
不应该是蓝盒子的。给我！
Not in a blue carton,
it's not. Give me that.
脱脂牛奶！
Skim!
－ 这对你有好处
－ 我不要什么好处
￡- lt's better for you.
￡- Don't give me better.
看，融化不了
Look, it's not even mixing.
咖啡甚至都不认识它
The coffee doesn't even
recognize it.
如果你不喝，我就……
lf you don't drink that,
l'm gonna￡-￡-
什么？你就会怎样？
What?
What are you gonna do?
离开我？
Leave me?
嘿，雷，等一会
Hey, Ray, wait a second.
就一会，儿子
One moment, son.
噢，弗兰克！
Oh, Frank!
嘿，再去拿一个袋
Hey, gotta get
another bag.
你妈妈要打包
Your mother
needs to pack.
弗兰克，健康展上的年轻人说……
Frank, the young man
at the Health Fair said￡-￡-
愚蠢的健康展
That stupid Health Fair.
我进去找杂货店买巧克力球
l go in there looking
for a chocolate cone at the drugstore,
谁知莫名其妙就被量了血压
next thing l know l'm getting
my blood pressure taken.
我的血压比你的健康
My blood pressure
was better than yours.
但我的视力比你好
But l won
the eyesight thing.
所以你们去测了胆固醇
想打破平局？
So did you have the cholesterol
checked to break the tie?
是的，我赢了
Yeah and l won.
我们还在等尿检结果
We're waiting for
the urine test.
如果你爸爸血糖高的话，我还是可以扳平的
l could still tie if your father
has high blood sugar.
在那之前我要吃我想吃的东西
天然鸡蛋和全脂牛奶
Until then l'm eating what l want
and l want real eggs and real milk.
那你最好去lHOP,
因为从现在开始
Then you better go to lHOP,
because from now on
在这所房子里我们必须吃健康食品
把那个给我
we're eating healthy in this house.
Give me that.
你在干嘛？
What are you doing?
－ 酸奶油
－ 不！
￡- Sour cream.
￡- No!
－ 熏肉，奶酪
－ 不！
￡- Bacon, cheese.
￡- No!
－ 你想把我的心也挖出来吗？
－ 烤面条
￡- What, are you gonna rip my heart out?
￡- Lasagna!
嘿，那个给我好了
Hey, l could have that one.
黄油！啊哈，巧克力蛋糕
Butter￡-￡-
a￡-ha, chocolate cake!
还有奶油煎饼
都倒掉
And cannoli.
All right, there. That's it.
－给你
－谢谢
Here, thank you.
你要去哪里？
Where are you going?
去野餐
On a picnic.
旧袋子出
Out with the old bag,
新袋子进
in with the new!
看，你根本不必用黄油
And look, you never
have to use butter.
人们现在都用橄榄油代替
They have olive oil
in a spray now.
闻闻，闻闻这个
Smell, smell this.
－ 噢，真香
－ 唔～
￡- Ooh, nice.
￡- Mm￡-hmm.
涂一点在你的耳后
You put a little of that
behind your ears,
弗兰克会神魂颠倒的
Frank will be all
over you.
－你这么觉得？
－唔～
￡- You think?
￡- Mm￡-hmm.
嘿，小粉红
Hey, Pinky.
嘿，黛博拉
Hey, Debra.
雷蒙德，黛博拉教了我好多烹饪技巧
Raymond, Debra's teaching me
so much about cooking.
你跟黛博拉学烹饪？
You're learning cooking
from Debra?
好吧，OK
Yeah, okay.
天堂在地下，地狱在天上
So heaven is here,
hell is here.
天上下猴子，木头可以当酒喝
lt's raining monkeys
and wood is now a drink.
看看黛博拉给我的书
And look at this book
Debra gave me.
“厨房健康101招”
"101 Healthy Things
to Do in the Kitchen".
在这个厨房，最健康的一招就是――嘿～～
ln this kitchen, the healthiest thing
to do is, whee!
噢
Ooh.
黛博拉在做饭
耶～耶～耶～
Debra's cooking
yeah, yeah, yeah.
我希望今年重新来过
l wish l had started
this years ago.
我觉得精力充沛，活力四射
l feel so snappy and peppy.
妈，我以为你这么做只不过是为了惩罚爸爸
Ma, l thought you were doing this
just to annoy Dad.
那是意外的奖励
That's a bonus.
玛丽，过来看看
这里有个专栏
Oh, Marie, come here, look,
here's that section￡-￡-
怎样过一个快乐的低卡路里感恩节
How to Enjoy
a Low￡-Fat Thanksgiving.
－ 噢，感恩节！
－ 是啊
￡- Oh￡-ooh, a Thanksgiving!
￡- Yes.
哦，我都等不及想开始了
Oh, l can't wait to make
some of these things.
哇～哇～哇
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa!
你不能这么对待感恩节
You're not gonna do this
for Thanksgiving.
就因为是感恩节才要这么过
Especially Thanksgiving.
你还是……
You're still gonna make
the real food
会为我们做真正的食物的
是不是？
for us though,
right?
我猜我会的
l guess l could.
不，雷
你妈妈不会做分开做两顿的
No, no, Ray, your mother's not
gonna cook two separate meals.
为什么不？嗯？
Why not?
Huh?
她爱烹饪，黛博拉
She loves to cook, Debra.
你凭什么剥夺她这个爱好？
Who are you to take
that away from her?
－看看这个
－唔
￡- Look at this.
￡- Mm￡-hmm.
豆腐火鸡？
A tofu turkey?
是啊，看起来不错，嗯？
Yeah.
lt looks good, huh?
我宁可吃那页纸
l would rather eat
that page.
书上说你需要一个特别的模具
Oh, it says here
you need a special mold
把豆腐做成火鸡的形状
to shape the tofu
into a turkey.
不，你不需要什么模具，妈
No, you don't need
a mold, Ma, okay?
上帝才需要
God does that, yeah.
他用一整团鸟肉
He takes a whole bunch
of bird meat
做成一只火鸡
and he molds
it into a turkey.
行了，雷
Come on, Ray.
我在宣扬圣经，黛博拉
l'm quoting the Bible here,
Debra, okay?
别担心，雷蒙德
会很美味的
Don't worry, Raymond,
it will be delicious,
就像我做的任何东西一样
like everything else
that l cook.
噢，我保证
Oh, l promise.
而且我不会忘记放最重要的原料
l'm not gonna leave out
the most important ingredient.
火鸡？
Turkey?
－ 爱
－ 爱？
￡- Love.
￡- Love?
你会没事的
You'll live.
OK，可以吃了
Okay, we're ready.
这是清蒸蔬菜，加了新鲜柠檬汁
Here's the steamed veggies
with fresh lemon juice.
噢，玛丽，看起来真不错
Oh, Marie,
this looks fantastic.
我一会就来
And l'll be right back
带着豆腐火鸡
with the tofu turkey.
就是我闻到的那股味道吗？
Mmm, is that what
l'm smelling?
端上来吧，妈
Bring it on there, Ma.
豆腐火鸡！
Tofu turkey!
我本应该坐在自己的公寓里
吃着牛排大餐
l could be sitting in my apartment
eating Beef￡-A￡-Roni right now.
OK，来吧，弗兰克
可以吃饭了
Okay, come on, Frank,
we're ready.
我弃权
l pass.
弗兰克，听着
Okay, Frank, listen,
玛丽为大家做了一顿很棒的晚餐
Marie has cooked
a very nice meal for everyone
你们得坐下来，吃饭
and you are going to sit
at that table and eat it.
－ 但我不想吃
－ 没什么好商量的
￡- But l don't want to.
￡- We are not discussing this.
我数到三。
一……
You have till
the count of three. One,
－ 我不吃
－ 二……
￡- l'm not going.
￡- two￡-￡-
－ 好吧，好吧
－ 很好
￡- All right, all right.
￡- Good.
看，这才像一个家庭
Okay, so see,
this is a family.
嗒～达
Ta￡-da!
唔
Mmm!
孩子们，看奶奶做了什么
Kids, look
what Grandma made!
啊？
Huh?
怎么样？嗯？
How 'bout that, huh?
看，还晃晃悠悠的呢
Look how it...
jiggles.
说明这是只好豆腐鸟
Yeah, that's a sign
of a good bean curd bird.
把刀子递给我好吗
May l have
my carving knife, please?
谢谢，弗兰克
Thank you, Frank.
刺穿我的喉咙算了
l wanna slit my throat.
好吧，我来
All right, l got it.
l got it.
好了，你想要什么？
All right,
what do you want?
给我一条腿
Give me a leg.
OK
Okay.
好吧，你自己挑
All right, we've got￡-￡- look, we've got￡-￡-
here's your choices.
这里是浅色的部分
We got the light￡-￡-
light over here.
深色的在那里
食用色素沉淀的地方
We got dark where
the food coloring has puddled.
行了，把这个给我
All right,
just give me this.
不是食用色素
是辣酱油和甜菜汁
lt's not food coloring.
lt's Worcestershire and beet juice.
看看，多聪明
Oh, see, that's very clever.
你干嘛不把你的狗带来，罗伯特？
Why didn't you bring
your dog, Robert?
我觉得沙姆斯基不会吃这个的
l don't think Shamsky
would eat this.
是的，不过我们可以吃它
Yeah, but we could
eat him.
来吧，罗比
尝尝看
Go ahead, Robby,
try some.
－ 雷蒙德怎么不吃
－ 我已经吃过了
￡- What about Raymond?
￡- l had some already.
－ 你没吃
－ 我吃了
￡- No you didn't.
￡- Yes l did.
－ 你没吃！
－ 我吃了！
￡- No you didn't.
￡- l did!
我吃了，就在这里
你看不出来，是因为豆腐又弹回来了
l did, from right here.
You can't tell 'cause it morphs back.
行了行了
All right, all right!
我们都要吃
We are all eating some.
弗兰克
Frank.
吞下去
Swallow it.
雷，雷！
Ray. Ray!
来吧，罗伯特
Go ahead, Robert.
我从没想过我会吃这个，
把花椰菜递给我行吗？
l never thought l'd say this,
but could you pass the broccoli please?
事实上我觉得很美味
Actually l think
it's very tasty.
轮到你评论了，黛博拉
You just have to make
an adjustment, right, Debra?
不如再回味一次？
Kind of starts out with an aftertaste,
doesn't it?
真的有火鸡的味道
lt has an authentic
turkey flavor.
而且好处是吃了这顿饭后不会想要睡觉
And the good thing is you don't
fall asleep after this meal.
那是我仅剩的娱乐了
That's all l had left.
果冻！
lt's Jell￡-o!
嘘，别这样
Shh, don't do that.
我去开
l'll get it.
谁会这个时候来
Who could that be?
希望是死亡天使
Hopefully
the angel of death.
－ 巴龙？
－ 是的
￡- Barone?
￡- Yeah.
感恩节快乐！
红帽子饭店
Happy Thanksgiving
from the Red Bonnet lnn.
吃啊，吃啊，吃啊
Gobble, gobble, gobble.
这是什么？
What is this?
节日香肠大餐
A complete Holiday dinner
with all the trimmings.
他是慈悲的天使
lt's the angel of mercy!
肯定是搞错了
This must be a mistake.
你订的吗？弗兰克
You ordered this, Frank?
你为什么冤枉我？
Why do you assume it's me?
因为你总想要气死我
'Cause you're the one
who wants to kill me.
没错，但我确实没订
Okay, but l still
didn't order this.
谁订的？
Who did?
不是我，妈
你自己也不会相信是我
Not me, Ma.
This melts in your mouth.
本来应该送到街对面的
l would've left it
across the street,
但是这东西不能久放
but l can't leave
perishables.
－ 这里有没有一个叫雷巴龙的？
－ 不！
￡- ls there a Ray Barone over here?
￡- No!
噢～～～～见鬼
Oh boy!
拿去吧，你不会想要作证的。快走
Take this. You don't want
to have to testify. Go.
雷蒙德
Raymond.
吃啊，吃啊，吃啊
Gobble, gobble, gobble.
你订了这个？
You ordered this?
是啊，做为饭后点心
Yes, for a snack.
到我家里去吃
For￡-￡- at my house￡-￡-
在这顿美味的大餐之后
later, later, after
this delicious meal.
大家都来吧，一起吃
Come on, everybody,
let's dig in.
嘿，我们还没做祈祷呢
Hey, you know what?
We didn't say grace yet.
大家快来，一起做祷告
Huh? Come on, everybody,
grace time.
噢
Oh!
噢，主啊，保佑我们
Oh, Lord, bless us
and these thy gifts￡-￡-
－ 雷
－ 黛博拉，求你了
￡- Ray.
￡- Debra, please.
还有您赐给我们的礼物
￡-￡-which we are about
to receive
你知道……
and you know￡-￡-
呃，非常感谢
你的朋友，雷巴龙
uh￡-￡- thanks a lot.
Your friend, Ray Barone.
我们开吃吧
Let's eat!
哦天哪，我闻到的是不是栗子填料？
Oh God, is that
chestnut stuffing l smell?
你们到底怎么了？
What is wrong
with you people?
难道不能为别人想想吗？
Can't you stop thinking
of yourselves for one minute?
－ 玉米松饼
－ 唔
￡- Corn muffins!
￡- Hmm.
知不知道这样会多伤你们母亲的心？
Do you know how much
this has hurt your mother?
我没说要现在吃，OK？
l wasn't gonna have
it now, okay?
我不想伤害她，我理解她的感受
别碰我的火鸡！
l didn't want to hurt her.
l know how she feels. Hands off my bird!
我来处理这里
你去跟她谈谈
l'll take care of this.
You go in there and talk to her.
我现在不能跟她谈
她正不高兴着呢
l can't talk to her now.
She's all upset.
她正努力尝试着做一些改变
She's trying to do something
for herself for a change
你至少应该支持她
and the least you can do
is support her.
是啊
Yes,
还有比雷蒙德更好的人选吗？
isn't it time you thought of someone
else beside Raymond?
谢谢，罗伯特
Yeah, thanks, Robert.
你下巴上沾了东西
You got a little of my stuffing
on your chin there.
嘿，你拿着那个去哪里？
Hey, where are you
going with that?
不知道，也许送给流浪汉
l don't know.
Maybe l'll give it to the homeless.
流浪汉！
他们吃得可比我们好
The homeless!
They're chowing down in some mission.
幸运的下流坯！
Lucky bastards!
听着，妈，你可以出来了
没事了
Listen, Ma, you can come back in now.
Everything's better now.
黛博拉把坏的食物都拿走了
Debra took away
all the bad food.
我是指……饭店的食物
l mean, the restaurant food,
all right?
行了，快来吧
So come on, come on.
Come back in, come on.
来呀，妈
Come on back, Ma.
Come on.
嘿，这是酸奶酪蛋糕？
Hey, is this
your soy cheesecake?
老天，看起来真不错
Boy, it looks great.
我现在还不想吃甜品
因为我要留着肚子吃饭
l don't want to eat that dessert now,
'cause that's gonna ruin the dinner.
妈，听着，关于订餐的事……
All right, Ma, look, look,
about the ordering￡-out thing￡-￡-
不，我知道，对不起
No, l know, l'm sorry.
什么？
What?
我知道你有多期待我的感恩节大餐
l know how much you love
my Thanksgiving dinner
我应该满足你的愿望的
and l should have
made it for you.
不，你应该坚持你想做的
No, no, you've got
to stick to your thing￡-￡-
不，你是我的儿子
No, you're my son
而我却让你失望了
and l let you down.
对不起
l'm sorry.
知道吗，妈妈
You know what, Mom?
没关系
That's okay.
没关系的
lt's okay.
别说了，别这样
All right, stop it.
Stop! Don't do that.
你把我套进去了，别给我下套子
You're letting me off the hook.
Don't let me off the hook.
我不知道你在说什么
l don't know what
you're talking about.
我应该支持你的
Come on, l'm supposed
to be supportive.
不，我太专注于健康、节食之类的事了
No, no, l got too wrapped up
in all this diet business.
我忘记了最重要的事
And l forgot
what was important￡-￡-
为我的家人做饭
cooking for my family.
听着
Listen...
你同样也很重要，知道吗？
You're important too,
you know?
节食
The special diet,
长寿，诸如此类
living longer,
whatever.
这些对我也很重要
That's important to me.
你真好，亲爱的
You're sweet, dear.
你应该为自己做点什么
No, look, you should
do something for you.
如果做这些能让你快乐
And if this is what
makes you happy,
你就应该去做
我会支持你的
then you should do it
and l back you up.
噢，雷蒙德
Oh, Raymond!
好了好了，放开我
All right, all right,
now you back up a little.
－ 好吧
－ 噢
￡- All right.
￡- Oh.
－ OK，行了
－ 谢谢你，雷蒙德
￡- Okay, it's all right.
￡- Oh, thank you, Raymond.
－ 对我来说这就是整个世界
－ 我知道
￡- This means the world to me.
￡- l know.
－ 过来
－ 不用了，没事的，妈
￡- Come here.
￡- No, it's all right, Ma.
－ 走吧，出去
－ OK
￡- Let's go. Let's get in there.
￡- Okay.
各位，我们来吃妈妈的感恩节大餐
All right, everybody, we're having
Mom's Thanksgiving!
为奶酪蛋糕留着肚子
Save room for cheesecake.
我在哪？
Where am l?
妈？
Ma?
我做了个奇怪的梦
l had the strangest dream.
噢，算了吧，妈
Oh, come on, Ma.
好吧，我饿了
All right,
l was hungry.
我该为你留点的，但我不想
l'd offer you some,
but l don't want to.
妈妈，你的节食计划怎么办？
我可是很支持你的
Mom, what about your diet?
Come on, l was supporting you.
你说我应该做让我快乐的事情
You said l should do whatever
it was that makes me happy.
我说过，但是……
Yes l did, but￡-￡-
你知道什么能让我快乐吗？
黄油
You know what makes me happy?
Butter.
黄油让我快乐
Butter makes me happy.
唔～
Hmm.
Oh, mmm!
以饭店的食物来说，相当不错了
This is good
for restaurant food.
那你的胆固醇怎么办？
不是接近危险区域了吗？
What about your cholesterol?
The danger zone?
我只是接近危险界限
l'm close
to the danger zone.
等超过危险界限了再担心吧
When l'll get into the danger zone,
l'll worry about it.
再说了，这是感恩节
Besides,
it's Thanksgiving.
好吧，至少我能帮上忙的……
Well, the least
l can do
就是帮你吃掉一点
is keep you from
eating it all yourself.
很好，我们坐下来吃
Good, let's sit.
Come on, you wanna sit?
－ 好的
－ 给你
￡- Yeah.
￡- Here.
－ 真好吃
－ Ok
￡- Oh, yeah.
￡- Okay.
你要来一点这个吗？
Oh, boy.
You want some of that?
给我土豆
面包
Yeah, let me have these potatoes, yeah.
This bread.
啊哈！
Aha!
我说啊哈！
l said aha!
你来这儿干嘛？
What are you doing here?
我在床上打滚
l rolled over in bed
突然发现旁边没有“玛丽长城”挡着我了
and suddenly there was no
great wall of Marie to stop me.
你的意志力还真强啊
So much for your willpower!
你到底想说还是想吃？
You gonna talk
or you gonna eat?
算我一个
l'm in.
嘿，我正好经过这里
想过来看看……
Hey, l was cruising by,
l thought that l'd come￡-￡-
嘿
Hey!
我知道了
l get it.
把豆腐和秧苗摆出来给罗伯特吃
Put out the tofu
and the Brussels sprouts for Robert.
等他去上班了之后，你们就开始聚会！
Wait till he goes on shift
and then party!
过来，坐下，闭上嘴
Here, sit down.
Shut up.
谢谢
Thanks.
喘口气，爸爸，喘口气
Take breaths, Dad,
take breaths.
要来一点肉汤吗？雷蒙德
You want some gravy,
Raymond?
要，要
Yep, yep, yep, yep.
－ OK，还要什么吗？
－ 再给我一个
￡- Okay, you want anything else here?
￡- Get me another roll.
－ 还有呢？
－ 那个怎么样？
￡- Whatever you got there?
￡- Here we go. How's that?
这里怎么回事？
What's going on here?
我们在支持妈妈
We're being supportive.
你的节食计划怎么办？玛丽
What about your diet,
Marie?
如果每天都很痛苦，活得长又有什么用？亲爱的
What's the point of living longer
if you're miserable, dear?
是啊，我每天都在思考这个问题
Yeah, l think that
every day.
我能来一个吗？
￡- Can l have one of those rolls?
￡- Uh￡-huh.
太好吃了
This is great.
每样都要
￡- Okay, l got one of each.
￡- Hmm.
这个也很好吃
This is great too.
感恩节又来了？
ls it Thanksgiving again?
是啊，这次是快乐的感恩节
Yeah, yeah, this
is the good one.
把他们抱起来
Come on,
pick them up.
我要来一点火鸡
We're gonna have
some turkey.
吃吧
Hmm, here you go.
吃啊，吃啊，吃啊
￡- Gobble, gobble, gobble.
耶～
Yeah!
橘子～
Cranberries!
你尝过这个吗？来一点
Did you try these?
Have a little.
那个也吃吃看，很不错
Take some of that.
lt's good.
翻译：lisa doll
yukii45@hotmail.com
谢谢观赏